

## Profile

Software Engineer, with knowledge and experience in back-end development in Golang, Java & Spring Framework, and Node.js. I have worked with different cloud technologies from providers such as AWS, Google Cloud, and IBM Cloud. Experience developing/administrating Apigee platform (Google API Management tool).

# Education

## Software Systems Engineer, ICESI University, Colombia

2014 - 2019

# Work Experience

## **Software Engineer at VMware**

February 2021 — Present

Colombia

Software Engineer II member of Tanzu MAPBU Buildpacks team, working with Cloud Native Buildpacks and contributing to open-source projects in the Paketo Buildpacks community (Cloud Foundry Project).

 Continuous improvement is made to the Buildpacks ecosystem focused on both Open Source and VMware-provided solutions using Golang, Bash, GitHub Actions, and other technologies following high-quality standards.

# **Software Engineer at Perficient Latin America**

May 2019 — February 2021

Colombia

Software Engineer for BrightInsight, a US healthcare company. The project uses Java 8, Spring Boot, CloudSQL, Spanner, Maven, and other technologies.

- The application architecture was improved with a redesign of the application, using a microservices architecture, following high-quality standards.
- A part of the deployment was enhanced with the implementation of Terraform modules using Golang.

## **Intern Software Engineer at Perficient Latin America**

November 2018 — May 2019

Colombia

An intern working with an application called "PSL Assistant", an artificial intelligence chatbot that helps the workers of the company in many things such as report time, reserve rooms and creates meeting sessions using Slack/Skype messages.

- The time reporting process in Jira was considerably enhanced by this application.
- Facilitated the scheduling of Zoom sessions and physical rooms for meetings.

#### **Details**

Colombia, +573122486653 bryanhenao96@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

Golang Maven / NPM Bash / Shell Java JavaScript / Cloud (AWS, GCP, IBM) Node.js Spring SQL / NoSQL Framework CI / CD (Jenkins, Terraform GitHub actions)

## **Hobbies**

Competitive programming

Geek and gamer in my free time

## Languages

English

Spanish

# Software Developer - Freelance at DrillApp S.A.S

May 2018 — July 2019

Colombia

Full-stack developer for a product called "Pitia", a software for monitoring and data collection focused on the petroleum sector, built with JavaEE, MongoDB, and React.

- Improvement of the application architecture through a redesign and migration of technology from Play Framework to Spring.
- The times at which data were displayed/processed were considerably improved.

## Backend Java Developer - Freelance at We Are Angular

August 2018 — December 2018

Colombia

Backend developer for a mobile application, using JavaEE, Spring framework, SQL. In charge of the support and maintenance of AWS infrastructure, using services such as Lambda, EC2, S3, CloudWatch, and RDS.

- The quality of the existing code was improved by refactoring it.
- A beta version has been finished and has been put on the Play Store/App Store ready to be used.

# Support man for the web platform - Freelance at Flavium Arena

April 2018 — June 2018

Colombia

In charge of providing support for Flavium Arena (a competitive tournaments platform for the videogame League Of Legends) solving bugs/issues. The application was built with Java, Spring, and MySQL.

• Improved the response times to problems/errors during tournaments.

# Algorithms and programming course teaching assistant at ICESI University

June 2016 — June 2018

Colombia

Assisted the professor with the tasks associated with the course and guided the students by solving their questions in each lab session.

Responsible for grading each lab and/or activity in the session.

- · Algorithms and Programming I
- Algorithms and Programming II

## Awards & Certifications

Qualified for ACM/ICPC Latin America North regionals, 2016

One of the Colombian best ECAES (national education test), 2018

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud Foundations, 2018